Hey...
Rin.
Get up.
Come over here.
It was just a dream.
You don't have to worry.
Huh?
Usagi
Drop
I can't tell what'll come tomorrow.
ashita no koto wa wakaranai
明日のことはわからない
This is different than making a sacrifice.
kore tte gisei to wa chigau
これって犠牲とは違う
Something about it is different.
nanika ga chigau
何かが違う
And I don't think of it as some sort of forfeit.
batsu geemu ja nante omowanai
罰ゲームじゃなんて思わない
So I just don't get why.
...tte nande na no ka wakaranai
...ってなんでなのか分からない
I can't quite wrap my head around it,
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo
ちょっと釈然としないけど
but your existence is now much more than just important to me.
kimi no sonzai ima daiji da nante mon ja nai
君の存在今大事だなんてもんじゃない
There's nothing in this world that doesn't come to an end.
owaranai koto nante kono yo no doko ni mo nai
終わらないことなんてこの世のどこにもない
I don't cry because I'm hurting.
naku no wa tsurain ja nai no
泣くのは辛いんじゃないの
They're the sweet, sweet drops of love!
ai no sweet drops sweet drops
愛の sweet drops sweet drops
I want to go on dreaming forever, you know?
zutto yume mite mitai ne
ずっと夢見てみたいね
I want to try and be more gentle, you know?
motto yasashiku shitai ne
もっと優しくしたいね
If I can be with you, I'm happy.
kimi to iraretara happy
君といられたらhappy
Girls are really strong, aren't they?
onna no ko tte tsuyoi ne
女の子って強いね
But sometimes, they can be really weak, you know?
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne
だけど時々弱いね
Our wishes are happy, happy, happy.
bokura no negai wa happy happy happy
僕らの願いは happy happy happy
And our days will be just as happy!
sonna hibi mo happy
そんな日々も happy
Just wanna make you happy!
Here you go. Make me one, too.
Granddad used to make them, too, huh?
I don't remember.
By the way, I kind of want my own kitchen knife.
Huh? Aren't you a bit young for that?
They make ones for kids, too.
Seriously?
Let me think about it.
Aw...
Anyway, eat up quickly.
We're leaving soon.
Babies are so cute, aren't they?
Yeah.
My name's Kawachi. I'm a relative of Kaga, Rin-san's father.
Rin-san... Rin's been living with me for awhile now.
Oh.
You are Yoshii Masako-san, right?
Rin's mother?
Um...
Huh? M-Me?
Y-Yes...
There's something I'd like to talk to you about in person.
I'll happily come to you, so just name a place.
P-Place? Um...
I wonder... Perhaps in the shopping district, at-
Sorry, but I don't actually have any idea where you live...
So cute!
More home-made stuff, Mum?
You made this flower, too?
That's right. It's called embroidery.
Wow, that's amazing!
When you get a bit older, I'll teach you.
Really?
Since you're really good with your hands.
So what are you going to do?
Can't say without meeting her first.
Look after Rin for me.
Daikichi...
This is important,
so make sure you have a good long chat.
Your mother's been looking forward to seeing Rin-chan, anyway.
Just as I thought. It's really close to Granddad's place.
Welcome!
Are you alone?
I'm waiting for someone else.
Non-smoking, please.
Watch out. It's going to spill!
I just keep getting more and more stressed out.
Yeah, I know how that is.
Americano, please.
Right, one Americano.
Will that be all?
Yes, please.
That's wonderful, Saionji-sensei.
Just what I'd expect from you.
Now, you just need to give each character a couple of traumatic past events...
Isn't that overdoing it?
No, it'll be perfect!
I don't get it.
Why would she go to all the trouble of
disappearing completely from Granddad's life...
...if she was just going to live right around the corner from him?
I'll leave it to you then, sensei.
Thank you for coming.
That's pretty careless of someone who's trying to make a getaway.
Mum, I have to pee!
I know. I know. Just hold on a little.
Yoshii Masako
Hello? Where are you?
I'm already there.
Souichi-san...
Not quite. I'm his grandson.
She's like a kid...
U-Um... Sorry about that.
You just looked so much like him.
It's fine.
Someone else told me that just a little while back.
Though now that I get a closer look...
I think Souichi-san looked a bit less rough.
Yeah...
I brought a photo of Rin.
Oh, thanks.
It's one of her from this year,
at a rice cake making party at her nursery.
Wow, she seems sort of...
...grown up, doesn't she?
Book: Strawberry Kururun
Somebody called you "Sensei" back there, right?
Y-You were watching?
But the name on it...
I use that name for work.
Sorry.
I'm kind of out of it. It was a busy night last night, and I had to pull an all-nighter.
Huh?
Did this job pull you away from Rin, then?
U-Um...
Apparently, you convinced Rin that you were the maid.
But did you do that from the moment she was born?
Um... It was because of work.
But it's also true that I was Souichi-san's maid.
I had already decided that I wasn't going to think of her as my daughter...
...by the time I became pregnant.
S-Sorry, I don't really understand what you're trying to say.
My work never sold.
And just as I finally landed a big job,
I learned that I was pregnant.
It's not really the sort of job you can have while raising a child.
But Souichi-san told me I should have the child.
I spent my days either working or sleeping, and grew fatter and fatter.
But it's strange. When Rin was born, she was so cute, and I couldn't help but love her.
What's strange about that?
So I worked myself to the bone trying to raise her and do my job,
all along telling myself I wasn't her mother.
But it was really tough trying to be a day person.
There were lots of meetings at night...
...which were impossible to attend unless I was awake.
Um... I heard Rin spent nights with you at an apartment?
Yes.
Did you ever go out, then?
Ah, when I said "night", I meant in the middle of the night.
I'd head out once Rin dropped off to sleep.
And sometimes, I'd have Souichi-san take care of her.
Rin sometimes wakes up in the middle of the night, even now.
Did you never think about how she'd feel if she woke up to find nobody there?
But otherwise, how was I supposed to raise a child on my own?
That's exactly why Granddad said the three of you should be a family.
Do you have no objections to me continuing to live with Rin?
I don't.
I'm no longer her mother,
so I have no right to tell her what to do.
Even though Rin grew inside you?
That has nothing to do with it!
How do you feel about her, anyway?
Is she important to you or not?
I-I don't know...
I do have just one favour to ask.
What is it?
When she goes to school, please let her use your family name.
Huh? My family name?
The other kids might give her a hard time if her guardian's name isn't the same as hers.
Could you just promise me that?
I do understand your point,
but I can't promise that.
She's been Kaga Rin all this time.
I don't think you can just change someone's name like that.
I'm a woman, so I'm not particularly attached to my family name.
There's no telling when it might change, after all.
Rin's a girl, too, so I'm sure she feels the same way.
But she's only six.
And besides, that's not really what I'm getting at.
Plus that's just how you feel, and...
There's only one thing that matters here!
"Rin", the name that Souichi-san gave her. That's all.
Goodbye.
Hey...
I'm a man, so I don't really get what you're saying,
but...
...I can talk to her about it.
Talk to her?
Don't you think it's cruel to make a kid
that young decide something like that?
I...
I've been thinking about what's best for Rin.
And I think it'd be more cruel to make that decision for her.
So I'm going to ask her what she thinks.
We'll decide together, and I'll let you know.
She's just no good. No doubt about it.
Who could abandon such a cute young girl?
It's completely nonsensical!
Ah, but she definitely worries about Rin, at least.
It's just that she's a little odd,
or maybe that she doesn't realise the mess she's making for others.
What are you saying?
Of course a mother's going to worry about her child!
If she really cared, though, she should want to see her!
Don't be so rash. She probably has her reasons. Here...
I wonder what your granddad ever saw in her?
Well, that's kind of the least of our problems right now.
The issue at hand is that she asked me to enrol Rin with my family name.
Oh. Well I agree with that.
Huh?
It's only natural that a child should
have the same name as her guardian.
That's... Well, I understand that, but...
How am I supposed to explain that to Rin?
She already has her own name.
Well, she's a girl.
When she gets married, her name will change anyway.
That again?!
What "again"?
If she's just going to go to school and be bullied for her name,
it'd be better for her to just use ours.
You think she can just get used to using two names?
Well, there are all sorts, even in junior school.
It won't be so unusual.
Then I'll adopt her.
What?!
As long as she doesn't mind.
Then she really will be Kawachi Rin.
Yeah, it'll be more natural that way.
Don't talk so flippantly about something that important!
I'm not being flippant!
We're going to have to decide this sooner or later!
It makes no difference if it's now or not!
Calm down. Calm down...
It does make a difference!
It doesn't! It absolutely doesn't!
I'm not going to pass the baton onto anyone else.
That'd be too much for Rin.
I can take anything that comes my way, if it's for her.
Box: Kitchen Knife for Kids
Here you go.
For me?
That's right.
But don't use it when I'm not around, okay?
If you can promise me that, you can use it.
I promise!
How about I make you curry?
Huh? Seriously?
Tonight!
Let's leave it until tomorrow...
Huh? I forget. Do I push? Or pull?
Huh? Give it here a second.
Ah, yeah, like this.
Daikichi, you're really good!
Well, I've been living on my own for a long time...
Go ahead and give it a shot.
Take it slowly, okay?
Don't drink the water.
Right.
Right. Go in up to your shoulders and count to ten.
Okay.
One... Two...
TL Note: Rin says a cute little counting rhyme here in Japanese. The nonsensical words she's saying contain numbers in Japanese.
Saury and mushrooms.
Three... Four...
Burdock and six alligators.
Seven! Eight! Nine!
Five...
Daikichi, you're too slow!
Don't eat it too quickly.
Yeah.
Hey, Rin...
What is it?
It's nothing.
You make really good curry!
Do you have to do it that many times?
Oh, no. It's fine.
Hey, you know...
I'm not your father.
Yeah.
And I'm not your big brother, either.
Nobody thinks that!
I'm just giving an example!
I'm asking what you think that makes me.
Daikichi!
That's my name!
Listen.
Assuming you don't mind...
Uh... How do I put this...
Um... How about I become your...
What would you think if I became your real father?
Daikichi... as my father?
And if we did, your name would be Kawachi Rin.
Kawachi... Rin...
No.
No?
Wouldn't it be better if you had a father?
My father is Granddad.
I like the name Kaga Rin.
It's the same name as Granddad's.
That's important.
I see.
Daikichi should just stay as Daikichi.
Daikichi...
What's wrong?
Are you crying?
It's sweat!
Sweating in March?
Shut up!
Just open your mouth.
I opened it and you started crying!
I said that I wasn't crying!
Move your head up a bit more.
Okay.
You know this'll always be your home from now on, right?
Yeah.
Sign: Congratulations on graduating from nursery!
We shouldn't forget what we believe in,
because morning is always just around the corner.
We shouldn't give up on our dreams.
They'll all come true someday, for sure!
The first step forward;
a step towards tomorrow.
Starting today, everything is new!
The first step forward;
a step toward tomorrow.
Gather your courage, and take a big step forward!
Orange Class
Understood.
You're going to get fat.
I don't care. I'm a waste of a human being, anyway.
Give me one.
No.
A sunny Sunday's early afternoon;
nichiyou no hareta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
where should we go today?
kyou wa doko e yukou?
今日はどこへ行こう？
The same old road that I'm so used to walking on...
kayoinareta itsumo no michi ga
通い慣れたいつもの道が
...shines with a dazzling light.
mabushiku kagayaite mieru
眩しく 輝いて見える
If I have the warm sunlight shining down on me...
terasu atatakai taiyou to
照らす暖かい太陽と
...and you by my side...
tonari ni kimi ga ireba...
隣に君がいれば
Whoa! High, high, high!
My feelings are ready to burst forth.
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice reaches every corner of the earth.
koe wa doko made mo
声はどこまでも
I'm already high, high, high!
mou high high high!
もう high high high!
Riding the whirling winds...
maiagaru kaze ni nori
舞い上がる風に乗り
Sing out, lai lai lai!
utae lai lai lai!
歌え lai lai lai!
My voice swoops up and down with me.
koe mo tobihaneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Ah!
Only kids get hugs.
That's what Sayaka-chan said.
What? No way!
Even adults have times when they want someone to hug them.
But they're adults! Why?
I don't really know, myself.
Will it be okay, even once I'm in first grade?
Of course!
I'll hug you whenever you want.
W-What?!
I'm sorry.
I should've hugged you before!
Huh?
I'll hug you next time you cry, okay?
What the heck?
Don't worry!
It's getting to the point...
...where I'm losing track of whether I'm raising Rin,
or whether she's raising me.